Guide to the Robert J. Kane papers, 1980-1992.
Kane, Robert J. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert J. Kane papers, 1980-1992.
40-1-2723
Kane, Robert J.,
11 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notes, drafts, financial records.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University.
Class of 1932; Director of Athletics.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, notes, drafts, financial records pertaining to the writing and publishing of GOOD SPORTS; also, correspondence concerning the United State Olympic Committee (1980-1987) and the 1980 Moscow Olympics. Includes John Marcham's memos and other material pertaining to organizing the book.
Also, subject, working, and reference files pertaining to Kane's Directorship of Athletics at Cornell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kane, Robert J., 1911-; Kane, Robert J., 1911- ,; Marcham, John.; Cornell University -- Adminsitration.; Cornell University -- Athletics.; United States. Olympic Committee.
Subjects:
Olympics -- 1980.; Athletics -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Book Finances (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Perkins-Corson (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Historical, ca. 1880 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Cornell (Box 1, Folder 4-13)
- U.S. Olympic Committee (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
- Jimmy Carter letter, February 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- U.S. Olympic Committee (Box 1, Folder 17)
- International Black Sports Hall of Fame (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Final Report on Physical Education and Athletics, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Corson-Anderson Letters, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ivy Budgets, 1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ivy Budget, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Ivy facilities (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Hockey and Wrestling (Box 2, Folder 7)
- ECAC Holiday Hockey Festival, January 1, 4, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Eastern College Hockey Association (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Syracuse Hockey Tournament, 1969 - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Pee Wee Hockey School, 1969 - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
- All-Star North-South Lacrosse Game (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Polo (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Rifle (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Sailing (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Skiing (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Track (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Heptagonals (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Squash (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Swimming (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Aquarius (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Tennis (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Soccer (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Wrestling (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Lacrosse (Box 2, Folder 29)
- ICAAAA (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Track and Field Hall of Fame (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Oxford-Cambridge (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Newsletter- Athletics, 1968 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Big Red Sports Wire (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Big Red Sports Wire, 1975 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Gifts Pending (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Big Red Sports Wire, 1973 - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Memorabilia, 1969 - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Robert J Kane Publications, 1971 - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Robert J Kane Publications, 1972 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Robert} Kane Publications, 1970 - 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Robert J Kane Publications, 1973 - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Eligibility- Ivy Committee on Coordination & Eligibility (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Varsity Football- Jack Musick (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ivy Handbook, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Athletic Director Candidates (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Assorted Papers (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Baseball (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Basketball (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Ivy NCAA Financial Legislation (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Ivy Policy Committee (Presidents), 1971 - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Clippings, Letters, Articles (Box 3, Folder 15)
- US Olympic Committee (Los Angeles 1984) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Articles (UAA & Senate) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Task Forces (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Alumni Field (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Newspaper clippings- Phys Ed. and Athletic Budget (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Response to Task Force #27 Report (Box 4, Folder 6)
- RJK memo to President Corson, September 2, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- President's Office- Annual Reports (Box 4, Folder 7)
- RJK Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Confidential Letter Mailing (Box 4, Folder 8)
- RJK Confidential, 1971 - 1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- General Correspondence, April - June 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- General Correspondence, January 1, 1981 - October 3, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- General Correspondence, July - September 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- General Correspondence, October - December 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- General Correspondence, January - June 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Advisory Panel on International Athletics (State Dept.) (Box 4, Folder 15)
- U.S. Collegiate Sports Council, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Gift Acknowledgements and Contributions, January - June 1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Gift Acknowledgements and Contributions, July - December 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Gift Acknowledgements and Contributions, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Publications, 1974 - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- RJK Speaking Engagements (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Department Reorganization, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Letters re: RJK Publications (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Class of '34 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Carter Task Force on Sports and Physical Fitness, September 5, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- F. R. Newman (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Floyd R. Newman (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Blacks in Athletics (Box 5, Folder 9)
- J. P. Routh (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Supporting documents attached to interrogatories (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Supporting documents attached to interrogatories, not attached (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Campus Life Division (Box 5, Folder 13)
- C.U. Fund Raising Campaign, 1976 - 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Development (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Football recruits, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Fund Raising CUAA, 1969 - 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Gifts (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Grohrnann, H. Victor (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Grounds Crew (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Grumman Squash Courts Addition (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Ivy League Economies (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Birge Kinne (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Memos/Information to Staff (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Financial Aid (Box 5, Folder 25)
- EAIAW (Box 5, Folder 26)
- ECAC (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Marine Midland (Box 5, Folder 28)
- AAU (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Admissions and Financial Aid (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Senate Ad Hoc Committee on Athletics (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Class of 1934 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Athletics Fund Raising at Penn and Princeton (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Memo from Accounting / Treasurer's office (Box 5, Folder 34)
- CUAA coupon books (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Fritz Krebs (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Lynah Rink (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Medical (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Memo - Inter Dept. (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Harkness, Ned (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Newman, F.R. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- General Correspondence, January 1979 - December 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Gen. Correspondence, January 1980 - December 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- C.U. Athletics, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Alumni Trustee, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Gift Acknowledgement and contributions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Correspondence on Athletes as Ambassadors (Box 6, Folder 8)
- ECAC (Box 6, Folder 9)
- C.U. Board of Trustees, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- C.U. Athletics Hall of Fame (Box 6, Folder 11)
- RJK Speaking Engagements (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Comp Tickets CUAA (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Bowling Alleys (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Admissions (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Coaches' Meetings (Box 6, Folder 16)
- RJK Town-Gown Appointment (Box 6, Folder 17)
- RJK Meetings-Luncheons (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Letters re: RJK Publications (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Board of Trustees Com. on Phys Ed & Athletics (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Equitation (Box 6, Folder 21)
- C.U. Hall of Fame (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Black Athletes Hall of Fame (Box 6, Folder 23)
- WHCU Administrative Board (Box 6, Folder 24)
- RJK Meetings-Luncheons (Box 6, Folder 25)
- National Association of Collegiate Directors of Athletics, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Physical Education (Program and Facilities), 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Women's Physical Education (Program and Facilities), 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- President's Office (Corson), 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Recommendations, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Reunion, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Scholarships and Financial Aid, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- No folder 8, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Tickets, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- World University Games, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Prospective Students, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Personnel Office, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Position Applications, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Special A wards, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- AAU, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Band, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Board of Trustees, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Broadcasting - TV and Radio, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Budget Salaries and Finances, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Board of Phys Ed. and Athletics, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Minutes, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Committee on Eligibility (Board of Phys. Ed. & Athletics), 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Buildings and Grounds, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Cheerleaders, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Colonnade, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Confidential Letter Mailing, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Cornell Council, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Cornell Club, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- ECAC, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Eligibility, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Endowment Funds, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Equitation, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Football Hall of Fame, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Gymnastics Club, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Intramural Department, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- General (Ivy League), 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Policy, 1970 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Ivy Finances, 1975 - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Ivy Fund, 1969 - 1970 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Ivy Sports Information directors (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Actions Taken at NCAA Special Convention, August 1975 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Mestres/ Litvack (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Ivy Athletic Equipment Policy (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Ivy Policies, 1971 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Chart - Distances between Ivy Schools (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Ivy Squad Sizes (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Ivy Budget Information (budget cutting proposals) (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Financial Aid Directors meeting (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Freshman Eligibility - Ivy (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Minutes - Ivy Deans and Directors of Admission (Box 7, Folder 50)
- All Ivy certificates (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Minutes Ivy Administration Committee (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Ivy FTE System (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Minutes - Ivy Policy Committee (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Ivy Meeting (Box 7, Folder 55)
- Minutes Committee on Coordination & Eligibility (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Peter Shier, Mario Tammaro Scholarship Fund (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Eligibility Cornell Cases (Box 7, Folder 58)
- Squad Lists for NCAA (Box 7, Folder 59)
- NCAA Student Athletic Statement (Box 7, Folder 60)
- NCAA Certification of Compliance form (Box 7, Folder 61)
- NCAA Special convention - Cornell, August 1975 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- AIAW/NCAA (Box 7, Folder 63)
- NCAA Postgraduate Scholarships (Box 7, Folder 64)
- ECAC- re: NCAA Special Convention (Box 7, Folder 65)
- Band (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Board of Trustees (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Budget, Salaries, & Finances (Dept.) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- ECAC (General) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Committee for 1971-1973, 1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- ECAC Finance Committee 1971-1973, 1971 - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Finance Committee (Box 8, Folder 7)
- ECAC Administration Committee, 1970 - 1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- ECAC Meetings and Minutes, 1969 - 1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- ECAC Meetings and Minutes, 1970 - 1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- ECAC Meetings and Minutes, 1971 - 1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Football Hall of Fame (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Confidential Letters (Box 8, Folder 13)
- General NCAA, 1964 - 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1A)
- 2 NCAA-AAU-Olympic, 1964 - 1965 (Box 8, Folder 2A)
- 3 Memoranda NCAA, 1965 - 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3A)
- 4 General (Olympic) (Box 8, Folder 4A)
- 5 NCAA-AAU-Olympic, 1965 - 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5A)
- 6 Nat' I Amateur Sports Foundation (Box 8, Folder 6A)
- 7 Memoranda (NCAA), 1965 - 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7A)
- Other Articles and Publications, 1972 - 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Alumni Affairs, 1971 - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- AAU (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Special Awards (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Band (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Broadcasting TV & Radio (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Board of Phys. Ed. and Athletics (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Budget, Salaries, and Finances (Dept.) (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Buildings and Grounds (Gen.) (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Cheerleaders (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Colonnade (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Cornell Club (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Cornell Council (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Confidential Letter Mailing (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Equitation (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Eligibility (Box 9, Folder 16)
- ECAC (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Faculty Matters (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Football Hall of Fame (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Intramural Dept. (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Judo Club (Box 9, Folder 21)
- RJK speaking engagements (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Letters re: RJK Publications (Box 9, Folder 23)
- RJK Dept. (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Board of Trustees (Box 9, Folder 25)
- RJK Dept., 1970 - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- RJK Speaking Engagements (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Letters re: Publications (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Lynah Rink (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Medical Dept. (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Moakley House (Box 9, Folder 31)
- National Association of Collegiate Directors of Athletics (Box 9, Folder 32)
- NCAA (Gen.) (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Ombudsman's office (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Phys. Ed. (Dept. facilities) (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Personnel (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Positions to be filled (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Swimming coach positions (Box 9, Folder 38)
- President's Office (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Women's Div. (Phys Ed) (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Recommendations (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Reunion (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Figure Skating Club (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Summer Program Athletics Dept. (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Tickets (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Traffic Control, Board of (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Letters re: Senate - Athletics & cutbacks, 1972 - 1974 (Box 9, Folder 47)
- CUAA and Senate (Box 9, Folder 48)
- Other Publications and Articles, 1970 - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Other articles and publications., 1971 - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 50)
- Eastern Intercollegiate Football Association (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Contracts - Football (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Baseball - General (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Contracts - Baseball (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Basketball - General (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Contracts - Basketball (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Contracts - Crew (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Crew - General (Box 10, Folder 8)
- IRA (Box 10, Folder 9)
- EARC (Box 10, Folder 10)
- NAAD (Box 10, Folder 11)
- 150# Crew - general (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Cross-Country - General (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Fencing - General (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Football - General (Box 10, Folder 15)
- 150# Football - General (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Freshman Contracts - All sports (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Golf and Golf Courses - General (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Contracts - Golf (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Gymnastics (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Hockey - General (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Contracts - Hockey (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Lacrosse - General (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Soccer - General (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Squash - General (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Swimming - General (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Tennis - General (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Track - General (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Heptagonals (Track) (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Contracts - Track (Box 10, Folder 30)
- ICAAAA (Track) (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Wrestling - General (Box 10, Folder 32)
- NCAA, 1973 - 1974 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- NACDA (Box 10, Folder 34)
- Prospective Students (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Recommendations (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Symposium on Sports (Cornell University), November 1973 (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Assorted Picture Frames (Box 10)
- Class of '34 Gift and Matching Gift. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Association of Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Athlete's Eligibility (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Awards and Honors (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Bob-Sledding (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Boxing (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Boy Scouts of America (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Coaching (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Commission of Collegiate Athletics (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Condolences, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Consulting Firms (Box 11, Folder 11)
- RJK Retirement, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Class of'34 (Box 11, Folder 13)